<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>Makenzie Bird</title><link>https://makenziebird.com/</link><description>Recent content on Makenzie Bird</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 13 May 2024 08:10:06 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://makenziebird.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>The Blank Page</title><link>https://makenziebird.com/articles/the-blank-page/</link><pubDate>Mon, 13 May 2024 08:10:06 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://makenziebird.com/articles/the-blank-page/</guid><description>90% of creativity feels like staring at a blank page. Sometimes the page stares at you back, a blinking cursor with the hopes of being pushed forward across the page, the hope of having words behind it. I always have the motivation to write, and personally, I feel like I have the technique to write, but never the ideas to write. Or the commitment to stick to those ideas.
Now that I have this blog (and I’ve always had this blog, but now that I’ve devided to finally use it) I’m going to force myself to commit.</description><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>90% of creativity feels like staring at a blank page. Sometimes the page  stares at you back, a blinking cursor with the hopes of being pushed forward across the page, the hope of having words behind it. I always have the motivation to write, and personally, I feel like I have the technique to write, but never the ideas to write. Or the commitment to stick to those ideas.</p>
<p>Now that I have this blog (and I’ve always had this blog, but now that I’ve devided to finally use it) I’m going to force myself to commit. To put things out there and claim them as Mine.</p>
<p>Also, hopefully no one finds this blog or reads from it. Nothing personal, but at the same time, all of writing is personal.</p>
<p>But if you are here (and by ‘you,’ I’m addressing my future self, who is the only person who should be on this website) feel free to check out some essays, poems, or short fiction.</p>
]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Well, well, well. An Error 404.</title><link>https://makenziebird.com/404.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://makenziebird.com/404.html</guid><description>You can head back to articles, opinion, and archives.</description><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>You can head back to <a href="/articles">articles</a>, <a href="/opinion">opinion</a>, and <a href="/archives">archives</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded></item></channel></rss>