<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>Grief on Makenzie Bird</title><link>https://makenziebird.com/tags/grief/</link><description>Recent content in Grief on Makenzie Bird</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2022 08:10:06 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://makenziebird.com/tags/grief/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>As Quickly as Gardens Grow</title><link>https://makenziebird.com/stories/as_quickly_as_gardens_grow/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2022 08:10:06 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://makenziebird.com/stories/as_quickly_as_gardens_grow/</guid><description>“She’s been sitting there for the past hour,” whispered the woman to the other.
The two women stood there, in the living room, studying the young woman in the armchair. She was stone-still, and if it hadn’t been for the slightest in-and-out of her breathing, the women would have assumed she was dead.
“You told her the news?” the other woman whispered anxiously.
Her companion nodded gravely. “This is how she took it.</description><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>“She’s been sitting there for the past hour,” whispered the woman to the other.</p>
<p>The two women stood there, in the living room, studying the young woman in the armchair. She was stone-still, and if it hadn’t been for the slightest in-and-out of her breathing, the women would have assumed she was dead.</p>
<p>“You told her the news?” the other woman whispered anxiously.</p>
<p>Her companion nodded gravely. “This is how she took it.”</p>
<p>The young woman looked much like her house, in the sense that she was tidy, delicate, and plain. She was well-kept and clean, with soft brown eyes that stared off, fixated on the patch of light in front of her that descended from the window. She sat, hands piled neatly in her lap, legs crossed at the ankles.</p>
<p>“Do you think she heard you? No tears? Nothing?”</p>
<p>“I know she heard me,” said the first woman. “And she’s just been sitting there in silence, ever since. That’s why I called you. Now try to talk to her.”</p>
<p>The second woman pressed back her shoulders and approached the young woman sitting by the window. “Adrienne?” she asked in a tender voice.</p>
<p>Adrienne made no sign to acknowledge her.</p>
<p>The woman sighed and tried again. “Adrienne, I know that Elizabeth told you what happened. Please react. It will be good for you, I promise.”</p>
<p>Adrienne didn’t move. A strand of hair slid out of her bun, and she made no attempt to tuck it back in.</p>
<p>The woman looked back at Elizabeth in concern. Elizabeth nodded her head, urging her on.</p>
<p>“I know how you feel. I went through the same shock when I lost Allen. But you need to react, to let it out. I know.”</p>
<p>Adrienne sat still for a second, then stood up suddenly. Elizabeth and the woman exchanged hopeful glances. But Adrienne didn’t say anything. Instead, she marched out to the backyard, opened the shed doors, and pulled out a spade.</p>
<p>The two women followed. They watched Adrienne take the spade to the middle of the empty garden the porch overlooked. Adrienne pressed the spade into the ground and stepped firmly onto the edge. The shovel sank in as though it was a knife and garden dirt was a stick of butter.</p>
<p>Adrienne repeated the action, carefully moving the excess dirt to the side. And then again, over and over until she had dug a hole two feet deep. A bead of sweat fell off her brow and into the hole.</p>
<p>The two women exchanged glances again.</p>
<p>Adrienne looked up at them, as though she had just realized they were there. She dismissed them with a wave of her hand.</p>
<p>Elizabeth led the other woman back into the house.</p>
<p>“What’s she doing?” the woman hissed.</p>
<p>“Just let her have her privacy,” responded the other.</p>
<p>Once the two had vanished into the house, Adrienne took in the solitude for a second before lifting her hand over her heart. In one fluid motion, she extended her hand as far out as it could reach, pulling out a dark energy that had once been inside her chest. She cupped her hands around it, collecting the swirls of darkness inside her hands, and threw it into the hole. Adrienne repeated this once, twice, until the darkness filled up the hole.</p>
<p>She shoveled the dirt back over the hole and patted the ground neatly with the head of the spade. Then she placed the shovel back into the shed, pressed the doors closed, and returned to the house without a word.</p>
<p>The next day, Elizabeth and her companion brought over some casserole dishes to Adrienne, but did not find her inside the house. The two women went into the backyard, where they saw Adrienne, tugging fiercely at a plant.</p>
<p>“You started gardening?” asked Elizabeth in a light, questioning tone.</p>
<p>Adrienne didn’t reply—instead, she continued to yank furiously at a plant that had sprouted just where the hole was yesterday. It was a small plant, barely budding, but its roots were firm and no matter how hard she tugged, shoveled, or yanked, it was no use.</p>
<p>“She won’t speak at all,” whispered the other woman, furrowing her brow. “Something’s not right here.”</p>
<p>Adrienne stood up and huffed, and pulled out a pair of gardening scissors from her apron’s pocket. She tried to snip at the base of the plant, but her scissors broke neatly in two.
“We’re here if you need us,” called Elizabeth, and the two women left Adrienne.</p>
<p>Adrienne’s hand flew to her chest. Another pain had started, another wave. She simply dug another hole on the other side of the garden, away from the stubborn plant, and placed more darkness inside the hole. After covering it up, she felt a little lighter, but just the slightest.</p>
<p>The next morning, another plant had sprouted where the second hole was dug. Adrienne tried to remove this one as well; her attempts were useless. Meanwhile, the other plant had started to spread, vines reaching outward and crawling across the patch of dirt.</p>
<p>Adrienne started to get worried. Another knot burrowed up in her chest. She told herself it was from hunger. She hadn’t even touched any of the casseroles brought to her.</p>
<p>But that didn’t stop her from digging another hole and casting more dark emotion inside of it. Her chest felt a little lighter, but she was still concerned about another plant sprouting up.</p>
<p>If she couldn’t suppress it, she could at least contain it.</p>
<p>Four hours later, she had constructed a wall about knee-height that wrapped around the six-by-eight patch of garden. She slathered concrete, pressed on a new stone, and then moved on to the next one. Over and over, until the sun was sinking below the horizon and her wall was finished. She left a small gap so she could get through. Adrienne placed the extra stones and bucket of concrete back inside the shed and turned in for the night.</p>
<p>The next day was the worst day. Adrienne donned a black dress, a black veil, and drove into town. She heard whispers, she heard condolences, she heard speeches. It wasn’t enough. The entire time, she pressed her lips together in a tight line.</p>
<p>A tear dripped down her face on the drive home. A raw feeling was eating up her chest, consuming everything. Fire burned inside of her. Something inside of her tightened.</p>
<p>This hole was deeper than all of the other ones, yet it filled up to the brim like the rest. A blister burned on her hand as she scooped the dirt to cover the hole. Sweat mingled with tears now, dripping over the hole.</p>
<p>She leaned the shovel against the wall, walked solemnly back into the house, and burrowed herself in isolation in her room. And, like her, the house was empty and still.
A week later, she emerged to check on the garden. It was chaos.</p>
<p>Vines crawled out of the ground, clinging onto the wall and trying to climb over. Shrubs offered their thorns and thistles. Undergrowth covered any spot of dirt. Flowers poured out of the ground, wreathed in leaves and strong aromas. Sprouts lined the edge of one wall.
Adrienne fell to her knees in shock. She didn’t know how to control this, how to tame this anymore. Her eyes burned.</p>
<p>She had to ignore it. Adrienne turned away and walked back into the house. She didn’t know what it would solve, but it was too much to go out and do something about the garden.
Weeks flew by, and the more Adrienne neglected the garden, the more it seemed to grow. Eventually, the garden moved beyond the walls, already reducing it to crumbled remains as the plants snaked and wove over the lawn and started up her porch. They invited themselves into her house. They shrouded the radio and television set, they covered the kitchen, they buried the table in vines.</p>
<p>One morning, Adrienne woke up and struggled to get out of bed. She found that vines with their wicked flowers had crawled up and trapped her, pinning her to the mattress.
Adrienne let out a yelp, the first sound she had made since the news. She found a loose gap in the vines and pulled herself out, tumbling onto the floor, which was already cushioned with shrubs and moss.</p>
<p>She stumbled into the kitchen and pulled out a knife. She slashed at every plant, every vine, every branch. Useless. The plants refused to react to her.</p>
<p>Adrienne stormed out to the garden and found the roots of the plants. They were buried under feet of bush and thorn and thistle, and more plants were already starting to sprout anew. She let out another noise of disgust as she climbed through the thorns, which stung her bare skin and ripped open small tears. She grabbed the shovel out of an entanglement of vines and plunged it through the plants, scraping wood and thorns. The metal shrieked and refused to reach into the ground.</p>
<p>Adrienne sprinted back into the house, her feet and legs being ripped apart by thorns. Inside the kitchen, she found a single match in one of the drawers. She walked out to the garden, trembling.</p>
<p>Her hands shook as she scraped the match, strong and fast, against one of the stones making up the garden wall. As she did, the garden wall crumbled, bringing several vines down with it. The match lit fire and burned endlessly, a small light contrasting the darkness emitting from the hole.</p>
<p>Adrienne tossed the match into the deepest pit of plants and sprinted to behind the shed, where the hose was in case things got out of control. The fire started slowly at first, but within a minute, the flames started to overtake the garden. The patch of dirt blazed merrily, crackling, until it spread over the grass. Suddenly the lawn was ablaze, and crawling into the house. Adrienne screamed and cranked the handle for the hose. A meek stream of water emitted from the hose. She unwrapped the cord and chased after the fire, trying to stop it. Smoke filled the air. Adrienne coughed and shielded her eyes. The hose would not be enough. She fell to the ground, choking on the smoke. Out of the holes she had dug, the darkness came right back and buried itself deep in her chest. Tears burst from her eyes as she crawled away, using the collar of her shirt to cover her mouth. The heat spread to her face. She stumbled away in the smoke, trying to find the shed, any landmark.</p>
<p>And then she let out a scream that became muffled in her choking. She could feel the darkness rushing out of her as the plants burned, as her house burned. And as all of it burned, the burning feeling inside her chest started to subside. The tears rushed out, an inky black staining the lawn. She dropped the house. She made it out of the smoke. She got in her car, drove to the neighbor’s house half a mile away, and phoned the firemen.</p>
<p>The next day, she came back to the remains of her house. Nothing was left, except for the armchair by the window.</p>
<p>She touched it with a single finger and watched it crumple into ashes, splintering as it hit the ground.</p>
]]></content:encoded></item></channel></rss>